<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Portfolio site</title>
    <link>https://benraguckas.github.io/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Portfolio site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://benraguckas.github.io/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final Year Project</title>
      <link>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-1/</guid>
      <description>My final year project that is focused on developing a full stack application utilizing microservice architecture, orchestration and message broker.
My goal is to deploy a full stack application with scalable and orchestrated structure for easier maintenance, upgradability, deployment and most importantly learning.
It is very early in development and nothing of it can be showcased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsagent assignment</title>
      <link>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-2/</guid>
      <description>2nd year team project (4 members) where we had to build a database access program in Java.
It had to be delivered in 4 sprints uzing Agile approach. Our objective was to gradually develop a this application to interact, manage and automate specific database usage.
Our final delivarable can be found on github page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timetable app</title>
      <link>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-3/</guid>
      <description>A personal project of mine to automate and streamline timetable viewing experience for my college.
What originally began as an Android Studio project has since moved to Flutter for ease of development, ease of building to different platforms and general performance issues I was facing. Although the project is fairly far in it’s progress it is difficult to showcase as majority of work is foundational and proper usability will likely only happen at ~85% completion with the remainder being polish of UX / UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio website</title>
      <link>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benraguckas.github.io/projects/item-4/</guid>
      <description>This very page that I built from scratch using HUGO.
It was an idea I had for a while that was pushed forward due to an assignment requirement.
It is still in its early stage most notably lacking responsiveness and higher level of polish.
Still WiP as I plan to improve and add to it to improve workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
